http://www.eifoundation.org/privacy/

Skip to main content
Privacy Policy
The Entertainment Industry Foundation, a U.S. 501(c)(3) charitable organization (“EIF”, “we”, or “us”) provides this privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) to describe how we may collect, use, and share information that you and others provide to us through our website located at eifoundation.org and other EIF websites, SMS text messaging services, or apps that link to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to our practices conducted offline (except with regard to donors’ personal information as noted below.)  EIF websites and apps that do not link to this Privacy Policy may have their own privacy policies that govern their practices.
Information Collection
You may voluntarily provide information about yourself when you use certain features of the Website. For example, you may choose to provide us with information when signing up for our newsletter, making a purchase, making a donation (which will also subscribe you to our email list if permitted under applicable law), submitting a fundraising proposal, applying for research funding, commenting on a blog, contacting us, requesting to volunteer, and/or using certain other services and features on our Website This may include information such as your name, physical address, e-mail address, ZIP code, billing and payment card information, phone number, date of birth, and country of residence.
If you submit a school club application, a research funding application, or a fundraising proposal, we may also collect information about your proposal, such as the associated school or company, the personal information of other individuals involved, and your title and contact information. By providing information about other individuals, you represent to us that you have obtained the consent of such individuals to provide such information to us. If you choose to participate in our third-party honorees program, we may collect medical information such as the honoree’s health conditions. Except in regard to such third-party honorees, please do not send confidential health information to us directly through this Website, or by email to any of the contact email addresses listed on this Website. If participating in one of our special promotions, such as our sweepstakes or contests, your information may be collected by EIF or by a third party involved in, or providing services in connection with, the promotion. If you choose to fundraise online on behalf of EIF, we may collect your name, phone number, and address.
We may also obtain personal information from third parties to support our operations, such as when you use the third-party links and tools described further below. Additionally, if you have provided us with information, we may combine it with information from third-party sources.
We may also gather technical information when you use our Website including, but not limited to, browser type, IP address, pages visited and other activities on the Website, online locations that you visited before arriving at the Website, device type, and time and date of visit. We may also receive information about your current location if permitted by your browser settings and we obtain your consent where required by applicable law. We may collect data regarding your interactions with our emails. We (or third parties) may use cookies or similar technology to collect such information for advertising and other purposes. See the “Digital Advertising & Analytics” and the “Your Choices” sections of this Privacy Policy to learn more about the use of this information and the choices available to you.
Information Use
We may use the information we collect for any lawful purpose, including, but not limited to, the following:
To provide products and services you have requested, including to process payments for products you have purchased and to provide communications and newsletters to which you subscribe; in this regard, please note that if you join or donate to EIF, you will be placed on our newsletter mailing list, if permitted under applicable law;
To process donations and applications, such as a club application or fundraising proposal;
To coordinate your volunteer opportunities and in connection with your online fundraising on EIF’s behalf;
To permit you to comment on our blogs, and to provide notifications of follow-up comments if you request such notifications;
To respond to your questions, concerns, or requests;
To ensure you are visiting the proper country-specific website, and when appropriate, redirect you to the proper country-specific website;
To send offers and advertising from us, our affiliates, and third parties, including opportunities to participate in sweepstakes, contests, and surveys;
To operate and improve the Website and our business;
To provide and personalize updates, surveys, and other content and communications to you, including to save your Website preferences to personalize future visits to our Website; and/or
As otherwise disclosed at the time of collection or use.
Information Sharing
Please see the “Third-party Links and Tools” section below for more information on how third parties may collect personal information in connection with our services.
Donor Information: When we collect your name or other personal information through a donation, we will not trade, share, or sell this personal information with any other organization or individual other than as disclosed in this Privacy Policy and in compliance with applicable privacy laws, nor send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations, unless we have the donor’s specific permission to do so. This restriction applies to donor information that we collect offline as well as through this Website.
How We Share: If we have collected information through the Website that identifies you individually, we may share this personal information with other parties including:
Affiliated companies and organizations, if permitted under applicable law;
Service providers or agents that perform activities for us, such as to third-party service providers as needed to process a donation, send our emails or host the Website;
Third-party partners engaged in fundraising activities for our benefit (for example, please note that if you donate through an individual fundraiser, including a fundraising appeal in honor or in memory of a specific individual, we may provide your name, message, and contact information to the fundraiser);
As part of a corporate sale, merger, acquisition, or other transfer involving all or part of our assets including as part of an insolvency or bankruptcy proceeding or as part of a corporate reorganization or other change in corporate control;
Pursuant to a subpoena, court order, search warrant, governmental inquiry, or other legal process or as otherwise permitted or required by applicable US or other law, or to protect the rights, privacy, property, business, or safety of EIF, its partners and employees, Website visitors, or the public to investigate a breach of an agreement or contravention of law;
As part of an effort to prevent, investigate, detect, suppress or prosecute fraud or criminal offenses or attacks on the technical integrity of the Website or our network; or
With your consent or as otherwise disclosed at the time of data collection or sharing.
We and our third-party service providers and affiliates may be located in the US or other jurisdictions, and may maintain and process your personal information in such jurisdictions.
Please note that if you opt to make a donation in connection with EIF’s promotion with American Airlines or similar promotions in which corporate donors receive incentives and rewards from partners in return for a donation, EIF will share the information we collect from you – including your name, e-mail address, loyalty program account information, and your donation amount – with the partner participating in the program.
When you respond to one of our blogs, or link to one of our social media venues, the personal information you share is visible to other users and can be read, collected, or used by them. For example, if you provide your name and e-mail address in a blog posting, that information may be accessible to the public. You are responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these instances.
We may share information that has been de-identified or aggregated, or any other technical information, without limitation.
Digital Advertising & Analytics
We may partner with social media tools, ad networks and other ad serving providers (“Advertising Providers”) that serve ads on our behalf on non-affiliated platforms. These Advertising Providers may use tracking technologies (including cookies and pixel tags) on our Website and other sites and apps in order to serve these ads. Some of those ads may be personalized, meaning that they are intended to be relevant to you based on information Advertising Providers collect about your use of the Website and other sites or apps over time (such as web pages you visit and your interaction with our advertising and other communications), including information about relationships among different browsers and devices. This type of advertising is known as interest-based advertising.
EIF adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) Self-Regulatory Principles in connection with this interest-based advertising activity. You may visit the DAA choice page at www.aboutads.info/choices or the Network Advertising Initiative choice page at optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1 to learn more about this type of advertising and how to opt out of this type of advertising on your browser by companies participating in industry self-regulatory programs. If you delete your cookies or use a different browser or mobile device, you will need to renew your opt-out choices exercised through these industry tools. Your opt-out only applies to the web browser you use so you must opt-out of each web browser on each device that you use. Note that opting out will not stop advertising from appearing in your browser or applications. It may make the ads you see less relevant to your interests. Additionally, your browser may offer tools to limit the use of cookies or to delete cookies; however, if you use these tools, our Website may not function as intended.
We may also work with third parties that collect data about your use of the Website and other sites or apps over time for non-advertising purposes. EIF uses Google Analytics and other third-party services to improve the performance of the Website and for analytics and marketing purposes. For more information about how Google Analytics collects and uses data when you use our website, visit https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/, and to opt out of Google Analytics, visit https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/.
Children’s Privacy
We do not knowingly collect, use, or disclose personal information about visitors less than 13 years of age. If you are the parent or guardian of a child under 13 years of age and believe that the child has disclosed personal information to us, please contact us at info@eifoundation.org and be sure to include in your message the username and/or e-mail address and password that your child submitted, if applicable.
Third-Party Links & Tools
The Website may provide links to, or otherwise integrate and share functions with, third-party websites or apps, including our social media pages, clinical trial services, social media fundraising appeals, and other fundraising tools. These third parties may share the personal information that they collect with EIF. We do not control the privacy practices of those websites or apps, and they are not covered by this Privacy Policy. You should review the privacy policies of other websites or apps that you use to learn about their data practices.
The Website may also include integrated social media tools, such as social networking, photo sharing, and video streaming tools offered by third parties. If you use these tools to share personal information or you otherwise interact with social media features on the Website, those social media companies may collect information about you and may use and share such information in accordance with your account settings on that social media platform, including by sharing such information with us or the general public. Your interactions with third-party social media companies and the use of their features are governed by the privacy policies of the social media companies that provide those features. We encourage you to read the privacy policies that apply to any social media accounts you create and use.
Safeguarding Information
The Website may provide links to, or otherwise integrate and share functions with, third-party websites or apps, including our social media pages, clinical trial services, social media fundraising appeals, and other fundraising tools. These third parties may share the personal information that they collect with EIF. We do not control the privacy practices of those websites or apps, and they are not covered by this Privacy Policy. You should review the privacy policies of other websites or apps that you use to learn about their data practices.
The Website may also include integrated social media tools, such as social networking, photo sharing, and video streaming tools offered by third parties. If you use these tools to share personal information or you otherwise interact with social media features on the Website, those social media companies may collect information about you and may use and share such information in accordance with your account settings on that social media platform, including by sharing such information with us or the general public. Your interactions with third-party social media companies and the use of their features are governed by the privacy policies of the social media companies that provide those features. We encourage you to read the privacy policies that apply to any social media accounts you create and use.
Your Choices
To opt out of our e-mail marketing and fundraising or to opt out of receiving our newsletters, you may use the link provided at the bottom of each such message or contact us at info@eifoundation.org. We may continue to send some e-mail messages related to our transactions or relationship with you, such as emails to confirm purchases on the EIF Shop. Additionally, please see above for your choices regarding digital advertising and analytics on this Website.
We may contact you periodically via phone or text message, including for marketing purposes, at a mobile number that you provide and after obtaining your consent if required by applicable local law.  We may call or text you using an autodialer.  If you would like to stop receiving calls and/or text messages from us, you can text “STOP” via reply text or you can register your choice over the phone or by emailing info@eifoundation.org.
If you believe that any of the personal information that you have submitted through our Website is no longer accurate, or you wish to make any updates or changes, you may do so by logging into the account you created when registering (if applicable). If you do not have an account with us, or wish to request to access, correct, or update your personal information in our records, including information not available through your account, you can e-mail us at info@eifoundation.org.
We reserve the right to use any information previously obtained to verify your identity in connection with your access request or to take other actions that we believe are appropriate and lawful. We will endeavor to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. To the extent permitted by applicable law, we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, are impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required by local law. Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes, and that residual information may remain within our databases and other records and will not be removed from such locations. We are not responsible for removing or deleting information from the databases of third parties that we do not control with whom we have shared information about you prior to your request.
Use of the Website from Outside the United States
We do not represent or warrant that the Website, or any part thereof, is appropriate or available for use in any particular geographic location. If you choose to access our Website, you do so on your own initiative and at your own risk, and you are responsible for complying with all local laws, rules, and regulations applicable in your jurisdiction. Please note that the Website is hosted in the United States and is governed by United States law. If you are visiting the Website from outside the United States, please be aware that your information will be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated, and may be accessible by the courts, law enforcement and national security authorities in accordance with the laws of the United States. By using the Website, you consent to your information being transferred to our facilities and to the facilities of those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.
Privacy Questions and Contacting Us
If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy or about our or our service providers’ privacy practices, or wish to access, update and/or correct inaccuracies in your personal information, please contact us at info@eifoundation.org.
Changes to our Privacy Policy
We reserve the right to revise this Privacy Policy at any time. Please check back regularly to see if there have been any changes to this policy, which you can determine by reviewing the Effective Date listed below. By continuing to use the Website after those changes become effective, you consent and agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.
This Privacy Policy was updated and is effective as of January 28, 2020.
